<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">RitchieGosling</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Dennis Ritchie!  Dennis MacAlistair Ritchie  (September 9, 1941 – c. October 12, 2011)  was an American computer scientist who helped shape the digital era. He created the C programming language and, with long-time colleague Ken Thompson, the Unix operating system. Ritchie and Thompson received the Turing Award from the ACM in 1983, the Hamming Medal from the IEEE in 1990 and the National Medal of Technology from President Clinton in 1999. Ritchie was the head of Lucent Technologies System Software Research Department when he retired in 2007. He was commonly known by his username dmr.Ritchie was born in Bronxville, New York. His father was Alistair E. Ritchie, a  longtime  Bell Labs scientist and co-author of The Design of Switching Circuits on switching circuit theory. He moved with his family to Summit, New Jersey, as a child, where he graduated from Summit High School.Ritchie graduated from Harvard University with degrees in physics and applied mathematics. In 1967, he began working at the Bell Labs Computing Sciences Research Center, and in 1968, he received a PhD from Harvard under the supervision of Patrick C. Fischer, his doctoral dissertation being "Program Structure and Computational Complexity".Ritchie was best known as the creator of the C programming language, a key developer of the Unix operating system, and co-author of the book The C Programming Language. Ritchie worked together withKen Thompson, the scientist credited with writing the original Unix; one of Ritchie most important contributions to Unix was its porting to different machines and platforms.The C language is widely used today in application, operating system, and embedded system development, and its influence is seen in most modern programming languages. Unix has also been influential, establishing concepts and principles that are now precepts of computing.</string>
    <string name="gosling">James Gosling!  James Arthur Gosling, OC (born May 19, 1955) is a Canadian computer scientist, best known as the father of the Java programming language.”/n”In 1977, Gosling received a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science from the University of Calgary. In 1983, he earned a Ph.D in Computer Science from Carnegie Mellon University, supervised by Bob Sproull.  Before joining Sun Microsystems he built a multi-processor version of Unix while at Carnegie Mellon University, as well as several compilers and mail systems.Between 1984 and 2010, Gosling was with Sun Microsystems. He is known as the father of the Java programming language.On April 2, 2010, Gosling left Sun Microsystems which had recently been acquired by the Oracle Corporation. Regarding why he left, Gosling cited reductions in pay, status, and decision-making ability, change of role, and ethical challenges. He has since taken a very critical stance towards Oracle in interviews, noting that "During the integration meetings between Sun and Oracle, where we were being grilled about the patent situation between Sun and Google, we could see the Oracle lawyer's eyes sparkle." Later, during the Oracle vs. Google trial over Android, he clarified his position saying "Just because Sun didn't have patent suits in our genetic code doesn't mean we didn't feel wronged. While I have differences with Oracle, in this case they are in the right.Google totally slimed Sun. We were all really disturbed, even Jonathan [Schwarz]: he just decided to put on a happy face and tried to turn lemons into lemonade, which annoyed a lot of folks at Sun.On March 28, 2011, James Gosling announced on his blog that he had been hired by Google. Five months later, he announced that he joined a startup called Liquid Robotics.Gosling is listed as an advisor at the Scala company Typesafe Inc. and Strategic Advisor for Eucalyptus.Gosling is generally credited with having invented the Java programming language in 1994. He created the original design of Java and implemented the language's original compiler andvirtual machine. Gosling traces the origins of the approach to his early 19s graduate-student days, when he created a pseudo-code (p-code) virtual machine for the lab's DEC VAX computer, so that his professor could run programs written in UCSD Pascal. Pascal compiled into p-code to foster precisely this kind of portability. In the work leading to Java at Sun, he saw that architecture-neutral execution for widely distributed programs could be achieved by implementing a similar philosophy: always program for the same virtual machine.For his achievement he was elected to Foreign Associate member of the United States National Academy of Engineering. He has also made major contributions to several other softwaresystems, such as News and Gosling Emacs. He co-wrote the "bundle" program, a utility thoroughly detailed in Brian Kernighan and Rob Pike's book The Unix Programming Environment. 
                             </string>
    <string name="about_rithcie"></string>

</resources>
